所以现在我们有我们的要求
so now that we have our requests
解析，我们知道它要求的是狂野的东西
parsed and we know it's asking for wild things
我们需要在响应正文中填写
we need to fill the response body with
那些野东西
those wild things
熊狮子和老虎
bears lions and tigers
哦，我的现在
oh my now
显然我们将不得不处理请求
obviously we're going to have to handle requests for
我们将在下一节中做的其他事情
other things which we'll do in the next section
但现在一切都是疯狂的
but for now it's all wild things
现在的情况
now as things stand
parse 函数返回一个地图
the parse function returns a map
响应体为空
with an empty response body
在我们的管道中，结果
and in our pipeline the result of that
被传递到 rout
is passed into rout
所以在我们的路线功能中
so down in our route function
这张 co 和 v 地图
this co and v map
已经有填写的方法和路径
already has the method and the path filled in
但正如妮可所说，响应正文是空的
but the response body is empty as nicole said
所以在我们的路线功能中，我们只需要更新地图
so in our route function we just need to update the map
包括响应主体
to include the response body like
像我们这里一样熊线和老虎
bears lines and tigers as we have here
我们不需要设置
and we won't need to set
我们在这里做的方法和路径
method and path as we're doing here
因为
because
已经在这张 co 和 v 地图上设置了
that's already going to be set on this co and v map
当它进入路线时
when it comes into route
现在我们之前已经看过这个 map 语法了
now we've seen this map syntax before
它是键值对的集合
it's a collection of key value pairs
所以我说让我们跳回去
so I said let's hop back
进入性生活，更熟悉灵药地图
into sex and get more familiar with elixir maps
当然
sure
我只是要复制这张地图并随身携带
I'm just going to copy this map and take it with us
我已经有一个 ix 会话正在运行
I already have an ix session running
所以我要把它粘贴进去
so I'm just going to paste that in
然后我要改变
and then I'm going to change
响应主体
the response body to be
一个空字符串，因为这就是
an empty string because that's how
这张地图要去
this map's going to
现在开始
start out now
我们地图上的键是原子
the keys on our map are atoms
所以我们可以使用 ceo 和 v 获取这些键的值
so we can get the value for those keys using ceo and v
那是那里的原子方法的名称
that's the name of the atom there method
我们回来了
and we get back get
如果我们想获得路径，我们可以这样做
if we want to get the path we can do it that way
只是需要注意的地方
and just something to notice
原子总是以冒号开头
atoms always start with a colon
并且这里的方法使用语法方法冒号
and the method here uses the syntax method colon
如果你正在使用
if you're using
原子作为映射中的键
atoms as keys in a map
这会很熟悉
this will be familiar
如果你用 ruby 编程过
again if you've programmed in ruby
但是会发生什么
but what happens
如果我们尝试获取一个不存在的键的值
if we try to get the value of a key that doesn't exist
像迈克一样，如果没有匹配的密钥，我们会返回 nil
like mike we get back nil if there's no matching key
所以我更喜欢使用点符号
so instead I prefer to use the dot notation
这有点严格
which is a bit more strict
我们可以说是骗局
we can just say con
小路
path
那会给我们回馈如果我以我的名义尝试
that'll give us back that and if I try it on my name
当我得到一个实际的错误时
while I get an actual error
在那张地图上找不到钥匙麦克风
there's no key mic found in that map
现在只需注意这个点符号
now just be aware that this dot notation
仅当键是原子时才有效
only works if the keys are atoms
所以我们要做的是更新响应正文值
so what we want to do is update the response body value
现在，如果您来自面向对象的背景
now if you're coming from an object oriented background
你会期望我们可以使用赋值语法
you would expect that we can use the assignment syntax
因为在oo程序状态是可变的
because in oo program state is mutable
所以你认为你可以做一个熟悉的任务
so you think you could just do a familiar assignment
像这样的东西
something like this
你把它分配到哪里
where you assign it to
例如熊
bears for example
但我们得到这个有趣的编译器部分是因为
but we get this funny compiler partially because
请记住，equal 是匹配运算符
remember that the equal is a match operator
但更重要的是
but more important is that
在 Elixir 中，所有数据结构都是不可变的
in elixir all data structures are immutable
所以我们不能改变
so we can't change
使用这样的赋值的 co 和 v 映射
the co and v map using assignment like this
而不是修改或改变地图
rather than modifying or mutating the map
我们需要将其转换为新地图
we need to transform it into a new map
我们通过调用一个函数来做到这一点
and we do that by calling a function
所以我要从头开始
so I'm just going to start at the top again
我们将使用那个 h 函数来获得一些帮助
we'll use that h function to get some help
在 elixir 中有一个模块叫做 map
and there's a module in elixir called map
只需按键和点，然后点击标签
by just key and dot and then hit a tab
它会做一些自动完成
it'll do some auto completion
我们想在地图中添加一个新的键和值
and we want to put a new key and value into the map
所以有一个函数
so there's a function put
你注意到它的真实性为三
and you notice it has an verity of three
这意味着它需要三个参数
which means it takes three arguments
所以如果我们看看帮助
so if we just have a look at the help
那么第一个参数是我们想要的地图
well the first argument is the map that we want to
更改将创建此地图的新副本
change is going to create a new copy of this map
我们想添加一个密钥
we want to add a key
在这种情况下是 b 和两个值
which in this case is b and a value of two
这将返回一张新地图
and that's going to return a new map
所以我们只使用 map put
so we just use map put
第一个参数是地图，它在我们的 co 和 v 中
first argument is the map and that's in our co and v
变量关键是响应体
variable the key is response body
并且价值是熊
and the value is bears
你注意到我们拿回了一张地图
and you notice we get back a map
有响应体
which has the response body
有了熊的新价值，但如果我们看一下 clv
with the new value of bears but if we look at clv
好吧它没有改变它有一个响应体
well it's unchanged it has a response body
等于空
equal to an empty
细绳
string
所以重要的是要认识到这并没有修改
so it's important to recognize that this didn't modify
这张 co 和 v 地图
this co and v map
记住所有数据结构和长生不老药都是不可变的
remember all data structures and elixir are immutable
相反，它会创建地图的新副本
instead it creates a new copy of the map
具有更新的响应正文
which has the updated response body
所以我们可以添加
so we can add
新的键值对
new key value pairs
但原始地图从未修改过
but the original map is never modified
所有转换数据的函数，例如 map put
all functions that transform data such as map put
返回数据的新副本
return a new copy of the data
因此为了捕捉新地图
therefore in order to capture the new map
由 pud 函数返回
returned by the pud function
我们需要将它绑定到一个变量
we need to bind it to a variable
是的，我们只是将它重新绑定到这个 con 变量
yeah we'll just rebind it to this co n variable
就像那样，所以我们使用了我们最初的 co 和 v 地图
just like that so we used our initial co and v map map
put 返回了一个新的副本
put returned a new copy of that
然后我们再次反弹到 co 和 v
that we then just rebounded to co and v again
这是一种很常见的方法
and this is a pretty common way to do it
我们只是改造了一张地图
we just transformed one map
进入另一张地图
into another map
如果我们现在好好看看 co 和 v
and if we look at co and v now well
我们看到响应主体设置为熊
we see that the response body is set to bears
正如我们所期望的
just as we would expect
现在更新地图是
now updating a map is
如此常见以至于有一个方便的快捷方式可以做到这一点
so common that there's a handy shortcut to do this
而不是使用 map put 我们可以使用这种语法
instead of using map put we can use this syntax
我们给它 cnv 然后我们使用竖线
we give it cnv then we use a vertical bar
我们给它钥匙
and we give it the key in
我们想要改变的值是响应体
the value we want to change would be response body
假设这次我们希望它是熊狮子
and let's say this time we want it to be bears lions
老虎
tigers
然后如果我们现在看看 co 和 v
and then if we look at co and v now
我们看到这也返回了地图的新副本
we see that this also returns a new copy of the map
响应体现在是熊狮子和老虎
the response body is now bears lions and tigers
要记住的一件事是使用此快捷方式
one thing to keep in mind is using this shortcut
你可以
you can
只修改地图中已经存在的值和
only modify values that already exist in the map and
我们已经有一个响应正文字段
we already have a response body field
所以这行得通
so this works
所以这是一个不错的小捷径
so this is a nice little shortcut
让我们继续复制这个
let's just go ahead and copy this
我们会将它粘贴回我们的
and we'll paste it back in our
路由功能
route function
所以我们将它粘贴在这里
so we'll just paste it in here
我们可以摆脱这条线
we can get rid of this line
我们的工作已经完成
and our to do is done
因为这会创建一个新地图
because this creates a new map that
也有响应体
also has the response body
所以我们有一个决赛要做
so we have one final to do
现在我们需要更新 http 响应字符串
now we need to update the http response string
根据地图上的内容
based on what's in the map
喜欢
like
我们不希望内容链接再被硬编码
we don't want content links to be hard coded anymore
我们希望这是动态生成的
and we want this to be dynamically generated
我们已经知道如何访问地图中的值
we already know how to access values in the map
所以这很简单
so this is pretty straightforward
我们在一个听码头里面
we're inside of a hear dock
我们可以使用字符串插值
and we can use string interpolation
所以不是这个硬涂层 20
so instead of this hard coated 20
我们可以插值
we can just interpolate
响应体的长度
the length of the response body
所以我们将使用字符串模块
so we'll use the string module
它有一个长度函数，然后我们将它传递给
it has a length function and then we'll pass it the
对话地图的响应正文部分
response body part of the conversation map
然后在这里我们将插入
and then down here we'll just interpolate
响应体
con response body
这应该照顾到这一点
and that should take care of this to do
如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
and if we save this away and run it
好吧，我们得到了回应
well we get our response
我们一直看到相同的输出
we've been seeing the same output all along
但现在它是动态生成的
but now it's being dynamically generated
因为路线被调用
because the route's getting called with
co和v地图
the co and v map
我们正在放置一个响应体
we're putting a response body
然后将其传递到格式响应中
and then that's getting passed into format response
我们正在动态生成该内容
and we're dynamically generating that content
所以本质上是我们最初的要求
so essentially our initial request
正在转化为有效响应
is being transformed into a valid response
通过一系列功能
through a series of functions
接下来我们将查看我们的第二个请求
next up we'll look at our 2nd request